ashampoo.com 2019-12-04

# Ashampoo® - Company - Privacy Policy

## Responsible party:

Ashampoo GmbH & Co. KG is responsible for data collection and processing. 

## Data processing for contract fulfilment: 

We process the collected data in accordance with article 6, paragraph 1, subparagraph b GDPR for the purpose of contract fulfilment. This also includes the associated customer service. If necessary, personal data are passed on to companies involved in the processing of this contract, e.g. e-commerce providers for payment processing or external suppliers of software components and products. 

## Data processing for direct advertising:

We process your data for the purpose of direct advertising, in particular for email-based ads. Data processing is carried out in accordance with article 6, paragraph 1, suparagraph f of GDPR and in the interest of informing you about new products and services. Each customer has the individual right to object to such processing. If they exercise that right, processing of personal data for direct advertising purposes will cease. Data stored exclusively for direct advertising will be deleted after the objection has been raised. 

Back to top    

##  Analyses 

In case of activation of the IP anonymization, Google will truncate/anonymize the last octet of the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA. 

Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. 

The tracking code embedded in this website uses display advertising. Remarketing as specified in Google Analytics for Display Ads is also used. You may find Ashampoo ads on third-party websites including Google. Ashampoo and third-party content providers, including Google, are using cookies. The combined approach of using primary cookies (e.g. cookies by Google Analytics) and cookies by third-party content providers (e.g. DoubleClick cookies) allows for interest-related ad development, optimization and display based on previous visits. You may disable Google Analytics for display ads at <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb> or customize the display of ads within the Google Display Network.   
We are using these Google Adwords-related features to also reach our visitors on third-party websites or internet users with specific interest profiles based on their internet use. We do not collect any personal data with our cookies, remarketing lists or other anonymous ids.   
By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above

**Google Signals**  
In addition we use the web analysis service Google Signals. Via Google Signals, Google provides us with reports on cross-device number of users, as well as different groups of users, based on different device combinations. In order to do so Google uses the data of users who have activated the option “personalized advertising” in their Google account settings. Google Signals is only used with activated IP anonymization. As a result, your IP address will be shortened by Google within the member states of the European Union or in other states that have ratified the Convention on the European Economic Area prior to its transmission to the United States. Therefore, no single user can be identified. You can withdraw your consent to the collection of your data via Google Signals, at any time via disabling “personalised advertising” in your Google Account:   
<https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922>

You can refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website: Disable Google Analytics   
You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore you can prevent Google’s collection and use of data (cookies and IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.:

**Please note:**   
This website uses Google Analytics with the code **"anonymizeIP()"** which ensures that IP addresses are anonymized. 

**Examples of data types also collected by Google Analytics:**

  * Browser type and version
  * Operating system and system language
  * Referring website
  * Host name of accessing computer (IP address)
  * Time of server request
  * Country/region of origin
  * Remarketing
  * Interest categories
  * Similar target groups
  * Other types of interest-related advertising

Back to top    

## Cookies 

This website uses cookies in several places. These cookies are used to make our services more user-friendly, more effective and more secure. Cookies are small text files that your browser saves on your computer. Most of the cookies we use are so-called “Session Cookies”. These will be automatically deleted after your visit. Cookies cannot do damage to your computer and do not contain viruses. Cookies can also be saved for a longer period of time, e.g. for a website to recognize your user profile without the need to log in. You can customize how cookies are handled in your browser settings. 

  * On some websites we use Google Ads. Google as a third party provider uses additional cookies to place ads on these websites.
  * The use of so-called DART cookies enables Google’s ad placement according to user visits on our websites and websites in the Ashampoo company group.
  * Go to [ Privacy Policy for Google Ads and the Google content network ](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) to deactivate the use of so-called DART cookies. [ Click here ](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

Back to top    

## Advertising

On some websites we make use of third party providers to place ads when you visit our website. These companies possibly use information (these don’t include your name, your address, e-mail address or phone number) on your visit of this and other websites in order to place ads on products and services that might interest you. If you would like to learn more about these techniques and would like to know what possibilities you have to prevent these companies from using that information, go [Click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

**Webgains partner program**  
This website participates in the partner program offered by Webgains (ad pepper media GmbH, FrankenStraße 150C, FrankenCampus, 90461 Nurnberg, Germany) in the form of text links, image links, ad banners or input masks. Information on website usage metrics, location of purchasers and clicks is stored as cookies and transfered to Webgains with the goal of optimizing our marketing activities. You can disable or limit the storing of cookies for certain websites in your browser. Please note that this can result in certain features of this website becoming less usable or unusable. Further details on data processing through Webgains are availble as part of privacy policy statement of the company at: http://www.webgains.com/public/de/datenschutzerklaerung/

**Criteo**  
This web site uses technology by Criteo GmbH to anonymously monitor and collect information about the surfing behavior of page visitors for marketing purposes. This data is stored on your computer as cookie files. Criteo employs an algorithm to analyze your surfing behavior and provide suitable product recommendations in the form of personalized ad banners on other web sites (called publishers). This data cannot be used to personally identify page visitors. It is only used to improve our product offerings. We will never share this information with third parties.

You will find more detailed information on the technology provided by Criteo and a way to disable it in their privacy policy at: <http://www.criteo.com/privacy/>. 

**CJ Affiliate (former Commission Junction)**  
We use affiliate networks operated by CJ (https://www.cj.com). Whenever you are referred to our website by an advertisement on a website that is part of these affiliate networks (affiliate), the fact that you are coming from that website will be recorded. For this purpose, the respective company will set a cookie. If you make a purchase on our website or revisit our website within a certain period of time, the respective companies will be able to recognize you and attribute any purchases you make to the affiliate. A random pseudonym will be used so that this information cannot be linked to you personally. We will not combine this information with your personal data nor forward any personal data on you to third parties. You can prevent being tracked by choosing the appropriate preference in the privacy options of your browser or disable cookies or delete the cookie.

**AWIN**  
AWIN Inc, DBA in California As Awin Global Affiliate Network of 8 Market Place, Suite 600, Baltimore, MD21202 uses cookies for advertising purposes. As part of its tracking services, AWIN stores cookies to document transactions (e.g., leads and sales) on devices of users who visit or use its customers' websites or other online offerings (e.g., to register for a product test or download or to place an order in an online shop). These cookies serve only the purpose of correctly attributing the success of an advertising medium and the corresponding accounting within its network. AWIN does not collect, process or use personal data. A cookie only contains information about when a device clicked on a particular advertising medium. The AWIN tracking cookies contain an individual sequence of digits which cannot, however, personally identify the individual user and with which the affiliate program of an advertiser, the publisher, the time of the user's action (click or view) are documented. AWIN also collects information about the device from which a transaction is performed, e.g., the operating system and the requesting browser.

If you do not want cookies to be stored in your browser, you can make that choice by setting your browser accordingly. You can deactivate the storage of cookies in your browser under Extras/Internet Options, limit them to specific websites or set your browser to notify you when a cookie is sent. Please note, however, that in this case you will have to expect a limited depiction of online offers and limited user guidance. You can also delete cookies at any time. In this case, the information stored therein will be removed from your device.

If you would like more information about AWIN's data handling, you can find it here: <https://www.awin.com/us/legal>

**Marvellous Machine**  
This website uses the retargeting tool "Marvellous Machine" of Maytrics GmbH, Graf-von-Stauffenberg-Weg 1b, 59379 Selm, Germany. Further information about this third party provider can be found at https://www.marvellousmachine.net/, the data protection declaration can be found under the link https://marvellousmachine.net/content/datenschutz 

Marvellous Machine collects pseudonymous information about user visits and interactions with your Web site for promotional purposes. Under no circumstances will the pseudonymised data be used to personally identify the user of the website. Cookies are used in this context, whereby data is collected and stored for retargeting purposes. Retargeting technology is used to collect anonymous information about the surfing behavior of website visitors for advertising purposes and to store it in "cookie" text files on your computer. The legal basis for this processing is in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 S. 1 lit. f) DSGVO on the basis of our legitimate interest in the display of personalised advertising and market research.

You can object to the use of the targeting tool on our website at any time. Please click on the following link: https://maytrics.marvellousmachine.net/cnst.php?cid=1826&cnst=0&js=0

**Microsoft Bing Ad's Universal Event Tracking**  
We use Microsoft Bing Ad's Universal Event Tracking for advertising and marketing. You can find more information about Microsoft's privacy policies at <https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/privacy-policy>.

**Mixpanel Inc.**  
Ashampoo Price Radar uses technology by Mixpanel Inc. ("Mixpanel") to perform statistical evaluations that enable us to optimize product functions and make them more attractive.

For this purpose, data on browser type, language, currency and region used as well as domains accessed is evaluated anonymously using cookies.

You will find a way to disable the Mixpanel technology in their privacy policy at:   
<https://mixpanel.com/optout/>

You will find more detailed information on the technology provided by Mixpanel at:  
<https://mixpanel.com/privacy>

**Push notifications**  
You can opt in to receive our push notifications. To send our push notifications, we use the delivery service "CleverPush", which is provided by CleverPush GmbH, Nagelsweg 22, 20097 Hamburg ("CleverPush"). By that you will receive regular messages about product news, latest features and updates, blog posts and offers and relevant information about Ashampoo.   
To opt in, you must confirm your browser's request to receive notifications. This process is documented and stored by CleverPush. This includes saving the opt in time and your browser ID or device ID. The collection of this data is required so that we can understand the processes in case of misuse and therefore serves our legal protection.   
To show you the push notifications, CleverPush collects and processes your browser ID on our behalf and your device ID in the case of mobile access.   
By subscribing to our push notifications, you agree to their receipt. Legal basis for the processing of your data after registration for our push notifications is in the presence of your consent Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. CleverPush also statistically evaluates our push notifications. CleverPush can detect if and when our push notifications were displayed and clicked by you.   
Your consent to the storage and use of your personal information to receive our push notifications and the statistical survey described above may be revoked at any time with future effect. To revoke consent, you can change the setting to receive push notifications in your browser. If you use our push notifications on a desktop PC with the operating system "Windows", you can also unsubscribe our push notifications by right-clicking on the respective push notification in the settings that appear there.   
Your data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer necessary to achieve the purpose of their survey. Your data will be stored as long as the subscription to our push notifications is active.   
Under the following link, the process of unsubscribing will be explained in detail: <https://cleverpush.com/faq>

Back to top    

## Newsletter 

If you want to receive the Newsletter we offer on our website, we need a valid e-mail address as well as, for your own protection, information allowing us to verify the address you entered and make sure you are authorized to use that address and consent to receiving the Newsletter. No further data will be collected. You can revoke your consent to the collection of data, your e-mail address and receiving the Newsletter at any time. Some of the software we deliver leads to an entry into several distribution lists upon registration. You are informed about such an entry before or during the registration process, so you can decide at any time whether you want this or not.

Some of the software we deliver leads to an entry into several distribution lists upon registration. You are informed about such an entry before or during the registration process, so you can decide at any time whether you want this or not.

Back to top    

## eCommerce

In order to process an order we need your address data, your date of birth, e-mail, telephone number (if applicable), the total purchase price, purchase order date and information about the handling of payments. 

  * To secure your information in transmission we use Secure Sockets Layer software (SSL) where needed. This software encrypts the information you submit. 
  * Of course this is also true for credit card payments. The credit card information is only stored temporarily and deleted after being handed on to the respective payment provider 
  * It is important for you to take precautions against unauthorized access to your password and your computer. If you share your computer with others, you should remember to always log off after each session. 

You can have your data deleted at any time. We use your data only to process your order, i.e. only information implicitly necessary for possible claims for reimbursement is collected and handled. 

Back to top    

##  Software Installation and Activation 

Activation, trial extension and unlocking of free software is achieved through an activation routine at program launch. This process requires an Ashampoo-registered email address and password. Alternatively, a license key can be used. Activation of a full version software requires an active Internet connection. During the process, a connection to a licensing server is established and a validity check performed. Invalid licenses / license keys or keys that have been used multiple times will result in the display of a licensing error in the program that will disappear once the program has been activated successfully. The validity of a product license will be automatically checked online at regular intervals. 

The following information is transmitted when you activate a program with a license key: 

  * The license key 
  * A checksum 
  * The product code 
  * The version numbers 
  * The language setting 

You can check your current license keys at any time. Just visit MyAshampoo at <https://www.ashampoo.com/myashampoo>. Your personal MyAshampoo data is protected against unauthorized access, you can log in with your email address and a password you choose yourself. Your personal data will be stored anonymously unless you choose to enter your name, which is entirely optional. Our privacy policies for managing your data are very strict and we will never share your information with any third parties. 

Back to top    

##  Other 

  * Promotions: From time to time we send offers by order of a third party company to selected customer groups. In this case, that company receives neither your name, nor your address or any other information that could be used to personally identify you. If you do not wish to receive such offers, you can simply stop them in your user account. 
  * Ashampoo and its affiliates can use the collected data for their own marketing purposes, in case you have agreed to this. 
  * The Ashampoo support staff uses the dependable Zendesk ticket system. Your data will therefore be relayed to and archived by Zendesk. You can find out more about Zendesk's data protection policy here: <https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/>
  * Service providers: We commission other companies and individuals to perform tasks for us. Examples are, among other things, package deliveries and payment processing (credit card, direct debiting, purchase on account). These service providers have access to personal information that is required for their tasks. They are prohibited from using this information for other purposes. Moreover, they are obliged to handle the information in accordance with this privacy policy and German data protection laws. 
  * Protection of Ashampoo and third parties: We will disclose accounts and personal data of customers, if we are bound by law to do so or if disclosure is necessary to enforce our General Terms and Conditions or other agreements or to protect our rights or the rights of third parties. This includes data exchange with companies specializing in preventing and minimizing the risk of violation and credit card fraud. We explicitly state that in this context no data will be passed on to those companies for economic use that would contradict this privacy policy. 
  * With your consent: In all other cases we will inform you if personal information is to be handed off to third parties and give you the chance to give your consent. 

## Right of objection pursuant to article 21 of GDPR

If data are collected based on article 6, paragraph 1, subparagraph e (processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller) or subparagraph f (processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests), you have the right to object to the processing at any time for reasons arising from your particular situation. We will then no longer process the personal data unless there are demonstrably compelling reasons that outweigh the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject, or the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. If possible, please direct your objection to: [support@ashampoo.com](mailto:support@ashampoo.com)

## Right to object to direct advertising 

We process your data for the purpose of direct advertising. You have the right to object to such processing. If you exercise that right, processing of your data for advertising purposes will cease. If possible, please direct your objection to: [support@ashampoo.com](mailto:support@ashampoo.com)

## Right to appeal to supervisory authority:

Any data subject has the right to appeal to a supervisory authority if he or she deems the processing of personal data a breach of data protection regulations. The right of appeal may be exercised in particular before a supervisory authority in the member state of residence of the person concerned or the place where the alleged infringement occurred.

Link to supervisory authority:   
<https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html>

Back to top    

## Right of access to personal data

You have the right to be informed about stored data pertaining to your person, the origin and recipients of such data and the reason why this data was collected and stored. Information will be provided by our data protection advisor [privacy@ashampoo.com](mailto:privacy@ashampoo.com). 

We maintain physical, electronical and procedural safety measures in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of personal information about our customers. These safety measures include occasionally asking you to provide proof of your identity before we disclose personal data to you. 

Back to top    

## Youth protection

Ashampoo's services are not intended for children and should not be used by them. Ashampoo does not knowingly collect personal data from children and does not send you a request to enter such data. Although visitors of all ages can use our website, we do not intentionally collect personal information from anyone under the age of 16. If we become aware, for example through a parent or guardian, that a child under the age of 16 has illegitimately registered with Ashampoo using false information, we will immediately delete the account and all associated personal data. 

Back to top    

## Further information

Your trust is important to us. Thus we are always ready to answer your questions about the handling of your personal data. If, at any time, you have questions that this privacy policy could not answer or if you wish to receive more specific information about certain issues, please contact our data protection advisor privacy@ashampoo.com. 

Dr. Uwe Schläger  
datenschutz nord GmbH  
Konsul-Smidt-Straße 88  
28217 Bremen   
Tel.: 0421 696632-0  
Fax: 0421 696632-11  
E-Mail: [office@datenschutz-nord.de](mailto:office@datenschutz-nord.de)

Back to top
